let questions =[
    {
        numb: 1,
        question: "A relation R in a set A is called _________, if (a1, a2) ∈ R implies (a2, a1) ∈ R, for all a1, a2 ∈ A.",
        answer: "A. symmetric",
        options: [
            "A. symmetric",
            "B. transitive",
            "C. equivalence",
            "D. non-symmetric"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 2,
        question: "The magnitude of the vector 6i + 2j + 3k is equal to:",
        answer: "C. 7",
        options: [
            "A. 5",
            "B. 1",
            "C. 7",
            "D. 12"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 3,
        question: "Producer gas is defined as which of the following mixtures?",
        answer: "C. Carbon monoxide and nitrogen",
        options: [
            "A. Carbon dioxide and hydrogen",
            "B. Carbon monoxide and hydrogen",
            "C. Carbon monoxide and nitrogen",
            "D. Carbon dioxide and nitrogen"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 4,
        question: "If A is a skew-symmetric matrix, then A² is a:",
        answer: "B. Symmetric matrix",
        options: [
            "A. Skew symmetric matrix",
            "B. Symmetric matrix",
            "C. Null matrix",
            "D. Cannot be determined"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 5,
        question: "SI unit of magnetic field (B) is:",
        answer: "A. Tesla",
        options: [
            "A. Tesla",
            "B. Gauss",
            "C. Weber",
            "D. Henry"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 6,
        question: "RNA lacks the nitrogen base of:",
        answer: "A. Thymine",
        options: [
            "A. Thymine",
            "B. Cytosine",
            "C. Uracil",
            "D. Adenine"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 7,
        question: "The domain of sin⁻¹(2x) is:",
        answer: "C. [-1/2, 1/2]",
        options: [
            "A. [0, 1]",
            "B. [–1, 1]",
            "C. [-1/2, 1/2]",
            "D. [–2, 2]"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 8,
        question: "Speed of electromagnetic waves in vacuum is:",
        answer: "C. 3 × 10⁸ m/s",
        options: [
            "A. 3 × 10⁴ m/s",
            "B. 3 × 10⁶ m/s",
            "C. 3 × 10⁸ m/s",
            "D. 3 × 10² m/s"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 9,
        question: "What is the term for a liquid dispersion in another liquid?",
        answer: "A. Emulsion",
        options: [
            "A. Emulsion",
            "B. Aerosol",
            "C. Gel",
            "D. Foam"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 10,
        question: "If f(x) = 2x + cos(x). Then f:",
        answer: "C. is an increasing function",
        options: [
            "A. has a maximum at x = 0",
            "B. has a minimum at x = 3π",
            "C. is an increasing function",
            "D. is a decreasing function"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 11,
        question: "Lenz's law is based on:",
        answer: "C. Energy conservation",
        options: [
            "A. Ampere's law",
            "B. Newton's law",
            "C. Energy conservation",
            "D. Coulomb's law"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 12,
        question: "To get carboxylic acids directly from alcohol, which of the following oxidising agents is used?",
        answer: "C. Acidified KMnO4",
        options: [
            "A. Alkaline KMnO4",
            "B. Aqueous KMnO4",
            "C. Acidified KMnO4",
            "D. Anhydrous CrO3"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 13,
        question: "The area of a triangle with vertices (–3, 0), (3, 0) and (0, k) is 9 sq. units. The value of k will be:",
        answer: "B. 3",
        options: [
            "A. 9",
            "B. 3",
            "C. -9",
            "D. 6"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 14,
        question: "Which device converts AC to DC?",
        answer: "D. Rectifier",
        options: [
            "A. Capacitor",
            "B. Transformer",
            "C. Transistor",
            "D. Rectifier"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 15,
        question: "A disaccharide is formed when two monosaccharides are bonded together by which type of bond?",
        answer: "A. Glycosidic",
        options: [
            "A. Glycosidic",
            "B. Peptide",
            "C. Ionic",
            "D. Phosphodiester"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 16,
        question: "Let f(x) = 3x + 1 and g(x) = x² – 2. Then f(g(x)) is:",
        answer: "B. 3x² – 5",
        options: [
            "A. 9x² + 6x – 1",
            "B. 3x² – 5",
            "C. 9x² – 6x – 3",
            "D. 3x²"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 17,
        question: "The resistance of an ideal ammeter is:",
        answer: "B. Zero",
        options: [
            "A. Infinite",
            "B. Zero",
            "C. One",
            "D. Very high"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 18,
        question: "Which of the following compounds is formed when benzyl alcohol is oxidised with KMnO4?",
        answer: "B. Benzoic acid",
        options: [
            "A. CO2 and H2O",
            "B. Benzoic acid",
            "C. Benzaldehyde",
            "D. Benzophenone"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 19,
        question: "If |a × b| = 4 and |a·b| = 2, then |a|² |b|² is equal to:",
        answer: "C. 20",
        options: [
            "A. 4",
            "B. 6",
            "C. 20",
            "D. 2"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 20,
        question: "De Broglie wavelength is given by:",
        answer: "A. h/mv",
        options: [
            "A. h/mv",
            "B. mv/h",
            "C. h/m",
            "D. m/hv"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 21,
        question: "The process of transmitting electric current through an electrolyte's solution to decompose it is known as:",
        answer: "C. Electrolysis",
        options: [
            "A. Electrolyte",
            "B. Electrode",
            "C. Electrolysis",
            "D. Electrochemical cell"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 22,
        question: "The point(s) on the curve y = x², at which y-coordinate is changing six times as fast as x-coordinate is/are:",
        answer: "C. (3, 9)",
        options: [
            "A. (6, 2)",
            "B. (2, 4)",
            "C. (3, 9)",
            "D. (3, 9), (9, 3)"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 23,
        question: "Which lens is used to correct myopia?",
        answer: "B. Concave",
        options: [
            "A. Convex",
            "B. Concave",
            "C. Plano-convex",
            "D. Cylindrical"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 24,
        question: "Drugs that prevent an enzyme's binding site from a substrate are known as:",
        answer: "C. Inhibitors",
        options: [
            "A. Messengers",
            "B. Poisons",
            "C. Inhibitors",
            "D. Receptors"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 25,
        question: "P(A ∩ B) is equal to:",
        answer: "C. Both A and B",
        options: [
            "A. P(A) · P(B|A)",
            "B. P(B) · P(A|B)",
            "C. Both A and B",
            "D. None of these"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 26,
        question: "Power factor of a purely inductive circuit is:",
        answer: "A. 0",
        options: [
            "A. 0",
            "B. 1",
            "C. 0.5",
            "D. ∞"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 27,
        question: "What makes a solution?",
        answer: "A. Solute and solvent",
        options: [
            "A. Solute and solvent",
            "B. Solute and solute",
            "C. Solvent and solvent",
            "D. None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 28,
        question: "If set A contains 5 elements and set B contains 6 elements, then the number of one-one and onto mappings from A to B is:",
        answer: "C. 0",
        options: [
            "A. 720",
            "B. 120",
            "C. 0",
            "D. none of these"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 29,
        question: "Unit of magnetic flux is:",
        answer: "D. Weber",
        options: [
            "A. Farad",
            "B. Tesla",
            "C. Henry",
            "D. Weber"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 30,
        question: "When the molecules of a substance are kept at the surface of a solid or a liquid, what is the name of the process?",
        answer: "B. Adsorption",
        options: [
            "A. Absorption",
            "B. Adsorption",
            "C. Sorption",
            "D. Desorption"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 31,
        question: "The area of the region bounded by the curve y = cos(x) between x = 0 and x = π is:",
        answer: "B. 2 sq. units",
        options: [
            "A. 1 sq. units",
            "B. 2 sq. units",
            "C. 3 sq. units",
            "D. 4 sq. units"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 32,
        question: "Which electromagnetic wave has the highest energy?",
        answer: "C. Gamma rays",
        options: [
            "A. UV rays",
            "B. X-rays",
            "C. Gamma rays",
            "D. Infrared"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 33,
        question: "What is the total number of Bravais lattices in the crystal structures?",
        answer: "C. 14",
        options: [
            "A. 3",
            "B. 6",
            "C. 14",
            "D. 24"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 34,
        question: "What is the order of the differential equation y'' + 5y' + 6 = 0?",
        answer: "C. 2",
        options: [
            "A. 0",
            "B. 1",
            "C. 2",
            "D. 3"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 35,
        question: "What is the SI unit of resistivity?",
        answer: "D. Ωm",
        options: [
            "A. Ω/m²",
            "B. Ω/m",
            "C. Ωm²",
            "D. Ωm"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 36,
        question: "Which of the following alcohols is not polyhydric?",
        answer: "C. Cyclohexanol",
        options: [
            "A. Propylene glycol",
            "B. Ethylene glycol",
            "C. Cyclohexanol",
            "D. Benzene-1,2-diol"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 37,
        question: "If A and B are independent, the probability of at least one of them occurring is:",
        answer: "B. 1− P(A′) P(B′)",
        options: [
            "A. 1 + P(A′) P(B′)",
            "B. 1− P(A′) P(B′)",
            "C. 1− P(A′) + P(B′)",
            "D. 1− P(A′) – P(B′)"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 38,
        question: "Basic material for making semiconductor devices is:",
        answer: "A. Silicon",
        options: [
            "A. Silicon",
            "B. Copper",
            "C. Iron",
            "D. Aluminum"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 39,
        question: "Which of the following should never be used to treat people directly?",
        answer: "C. Disinfectants",
        options: [
            "A. Antiseptics",
            "B. Antimalarials",
            "C. Disinfectants",
            "D. Antibiotics"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 40,
        question: "Which of the following is a type of Linear programming problem?",
        answer: "D. All of the above",
        options: [
            "A. Manufacturing problem",
            "B. Diet problem",
            "C. Transportation problems",
            "D. All of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 41,
        question: "Which wave is used in satellite communication?",
        answer: "C. Microwave",
        options: [
            "A. Infrared",
            "B. Radio wave",
            "C. Microwave",
            "D. Ultraviolet"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 42,
        question: "Which solid structure has a definite and sharp melting point?",
        answer: "D. Crystalline solids",
        options: [
            "A. All types of solids",
            "B. No type of solid",
            "C. Amorphous solids",
            "D. Crystalline solids"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 43,
        question: "The side of an equilateral triangle is increasing at the rate of 2 cm/s. The rate at which area increases when the side is 10 is:",
        answer: "D. 10√3 cm²/s",
        options: [
            "A. 10 cm²/s",
            "B. 10/3 cm²/s",
            "C. √3 cm²/s",
            "D. 10√3 cm²/s"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 44,
        question: "Which law gives the force between two current-carrying conductors?",
        answer: "C. Biot-Savart law",
        options: [
            "A. Ampere's law",
            "B. Faraday's law",
            "C. Biot-Savart law",
            "D. Lenz's law"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 45,
        question: "The aromatic primary amine with the formula C₇H₉N has an incorrect name:",
        answer: "A. Phenylaminomethane",
        options: [
            "A. Phenylaminomethane",
            "B. Benzylamine",
            "C. Benzenamine",
            "D. Phenylmethanamine"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 46,
        question: "The curve for which the slope of the tangent at any point is equal to the ratio of abscissa to ordinate is:",
        answer: "D. hyperbola",
        options: [
            "A. ellipse",
            "B. parabola",
            "C. circle",
            "D. hyperbola"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 47,
        question: "Which modulation is used in radio broadcasting?",
        answer: "A. Amplitude Modulation (AM)",
        options: [
            "A. Amplitude Modulation (AM)",
            "B. Frequency Modulation (FM)",
            "C. Phase Modulation (PM)",
            "D. Pulse Modulation (PAM)"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 48,
        question: "Reactions that occur between aldehydes and ketones are:",
        answer: "A. Nucleophilic addition",
        options: [
            "A. Nucleophilic addition",
            "B. Electrophilic substitution",
            "C. Electrophilic addition",
            "D. Nucleophilic substitution"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 49,
        question: "Time period is a:",
        answer: "B. Scalar quantity",
        options: [
            "A. Vector quantity",
            "B. Scalar quantity",
            "C. Neither scalar nor vector",
            "D. None of these"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 50,
        question: "What effect does temperature have on the half-life of a first-order reaction?",
        answer: "B. It decreases",
        options: [
            "A. It increases",
            "B. It decreases",
            "C. It remains the same",
            "D. Both increases as well as decrease"
        ]
    }
]


      /*  let questions = [
            {
                numb: 1,
                question: "Which solid structure has a definite and sharp melting point?",
                answer: "D. Crystalline solids",
                options: [
                    "A. All types of solids ",
                    "B. No type of solid",
                    "C. Amorphous solids	",
                    "D. Crystalline solids"
                ]
            },
            {
                numb: 2,
                question: "__ is a crystalline solid’s basic repetitive structural unit.",
                answer: "C. Unit cell",
                options: [
                    "A.Monomer	",
                    "B. Molecule",
                    "C. Unit cell",
                    "D. Atom"
                ]
            },
            {
                numb: 3,
                question: "Sulfur exists in two polymorphic forms ___ and ___",
                answer: "A. rhombic and monoclinic",
                options: [
                    "A. rhombic and monoclinic",
                    "B. rhombic and triclinic",
                    "C. hexagonal and triclinic",
                    "D. hexagonal and monoclinic"
                ]
            },
            {
                numb: 4,
                question: "What is the total number of Bravais lattices in the crystal structures?",
                answer: "C.14",
                options: [
                    "A. 3	",
                    "B.6",
                    "C.14",
                    "D. 24"
                ]
            },
            {
                numb: 5,
                question: "Which of the following claims about crystal lattice diffraction patterns is correct?",
                answer: "A. Diffraction patterns possess a centre of symmetry",
                options: [
                    "A. Diffraction patterns possess a centre of symmetry",
                    "B. Diffraction patterns don’t have centre of symmetry",
                    "C. Diffraction patterns are linear space",
                    "D. Diffraction patterns contains α-rays"
                ]
            },
        
            {
                numb: 6,
                question: "The volume occupied by a single gas in a mixture at the same temperature and pressure is referred to as the single-gas volume.",
                answer: "A. Absolute volume",
                options: [
                    "A. Absolute volume",
                    "B. Partial volume",
                    "C. Total volume of a gas mixtureg",
                    "D. None of the above"
                ]
            },
        
            {
                numb:7,
                question: "When two perfect solutions with volume V each are combined, What is the volume of the solution as a result?",
                answer: "B. 2V",
                options: [
                    "A. V",
                    "B. 2V",
                    "C. Greater than 2V",
                    "D. Less than 2V"
                ]
        
            },
        
            {
                numb:8,
                question: "What is an example of camphor in N2 gas?",
                answer: "A. Solid in gas solution",
                options: [
                    "A. Solid in gas solution",
                    "B. Gas in gas solution",
                    "C. Solid in liquid solution",
                    "D. Liquid in gas solution"
                ]
        
            },
        
            {
                numb:9,
                question: "What happens when a solute crystal is added to a supersaturated solution?",
                answer: "D. The solute precipitates out of the solution",
                options: [
                    "A. It becomes a colloidal solution",
                    "B. The solute dissolves in the solution",
                    "C. The solution desaturates",
                    "D. The solute precipitates out of the solution"
                ]
        
            },
        
            {
                numb:10,
                question: "The solute precipitates out of the solution",
                answer: "A. Solute and solvent",
                options: [
                    "A. Solute and solvent",
                    "B. Solute and solute",
                    "C.Solvent and solvent	",
                    "D. None of the above"
                ]
            },
            {
                numb:11,
                question: "A cathode and an anode are the most common components of an electrochemical cell. Which of the following claims about the cathode is correct?",
                answer: "B. Electrons move into the cathode",
                options: [
                    "A. Oxidation occurs at the cathode		",
                    "B. Electrons move into the cathode",
                    "C.Solvent and solventUsually denoted by a negative sign",
                    "D. Is usually made up of insulating material"
                ]
            },
            {
                numb:12,
                question: "Which of the following does not belong in the category of electrochemical cells?",
                answer: "B. Photovoltaic cell",
                options: [
                    "A. Voltaic cell		",
                    "B. Photovoltaic cell",
                    "C.Electrolytic cell	",
                    "D. Fuel Cell"
                ]
            },
            {
                numb:13,
                question: "Which of the following assertions about the main cell is correct?",
                answer: "A. An example of a primary cell is a mercury cell",
                options: [
                    "A. An example of a primary cell is a mercury cell",
                    "B. An example of a primary cell is a nickel-cadmium storage cell",
                    "C.The electrode reactions can be reversed",
                    "D. It can be recharged"
                ]
            },
            {
                numb:14,
                question: "In a dry cell, which of the following is the electrolyte?",
                answer: "C.Ammonium chloride",
                options: [
                    "A. Potassium hydroxide			",
                    "B.Sulphuric acid",
                    "C.Ammonium chloride",
                    "D. Manganese dioxide"
                ]
            },
            {
                numb:15,
                question: "Which of the following statements about a lead storage cell (or a lead-acid battery) is false?",
                answer: "A.It is a primary cell	",
                options: [
                    "A.It is a primary cell",
                    "B. The cathode is made up of lead(IV) oxide",
                    "C.The anode is made up of lead",
                    "D. The electrolyte used is an aqueous solution of sulphuric acid"
                ]
            },
        {
            "numb": 16,
            "question": "Which charge configuration produces a uniform electric field?",
            "answer": "C. uniformly charged infinite plane",
            "options": [
                "A. point charge",
                "B. uniformly charged infinite line",
                "C. uniformly charged infinite plane",
                "D. uniformly charged spherical shell"
            ]
        },
        {
            "numb": 17,
            "question": "An electric dipole is placed at an alignment angle of 30° with an electric field of 2 × 10^5 N C^−1. It experiences a torque equal to 8 N m. The charge on the dipole if the dipole length is 1 cm is",
            "answer": "(c) 5 mC",
            "options": [
                "(a) 4 mC",
                "(b) 8 mC",
                "(c) 5 mC",
                "(d) 7 mC"
            ]
        },
        {
            "numb": 18,
            "question": "Two identical conducting balls having positive charges q1 and q2 are separated by a centre to centre distance r. If they are made to touch each other and then separated to the same distance, the force between them will be",
            "answer": "(b) same as before",
            "options": [
                "(a) less than before",
                "(b) same as before",
                "(c) more than before",
                "(d) zero"
            ]
        },
        {
            "numb": 19,
            "question": "Two points A and B are maintained at a potential of 7 V and -4 V respectively. The work done in moving 50 electrons from A to B is",
            "answer": "(b) -8.80 × 10^−17 J",
            "options": [
                "(a) 8.80 × 10^−17 J",
                "(b) -8.80 × 10^−17 J",
                "(c) 4.40 × 10^−17 J",
                "(d) 5.80 × 10^−17 J"
            ]
        },
        {
            "numb": 20,
            "question": "A parallel plate capacitor stores a charge Q at a voltage V. Suppose the area of the parallel plate capacitor and the distance between the plates are each doubled then which is the quantity that will change?",
            "answer": "(a) Capacitance",
            "options": [
                "(a) Capacitance",
                "(b) Charge",
                "(c) Voltage",
                "(d) Energy density"
            ]
        },
        {
            "numb": 21,
            "question": "One of the combinations from the fundamental physical constants is hc/G. The unit of this expression is",
            "answer": "(c) s^−1",
            "options": [
                "(a) kg^2",
                "(b) m^3",
                "(c) s^−1",
                "(d) m"
            ]
        },
        {
            "numb": 22,
            "question": "The length of a body is measured as 3.51 m, if the accuracy is 0.01m, then the percentage error in the measurement is",
            "answer": "(c) 0.28%",
            "options": [
                "(a) 351%",
                "(b) 1%",
                "(c) 0.28%",
                "(d) 0.035%"
            ]
        },
        {
            "numb": 23,
            "question": "If π = 3.14, then the value of π^2 is",
            "answer": "(b) 9.860",
            "options": [
                "(a) 9.8596",
                "(b) 9.860",
                "(c) 9.86",
                "(d) 9.9"
            ]
        },
        {
            "numb": 24,
            "question": "Which of the following pairs of physical quantities have the same dimension?",
            "answer": "d) force and torque",
            "options": [
                "a) force and power",
                "b) torque and energy",
                "c) torque and power",
                "d) force and torque"
            ]
        },
        {
            "numb": 25,
            "question": "The dimension of (μ0 ε0)^−1/2 is",
            "answer": "(a) length",
            "options": [
                "(a) length",
                "(b) time",
                "(c) velocity",
                "(d) force"
            ]
        },
        {
            "numb": 26,
            "question": "Which one of the following physical quantities cannot be represented by a scalar?",
            "answer": "(c) momentum",
            "options": [
                "(a) Mass",
                "(b) length",
                "(c) momentum",
                "(d) magnitude of acceleration"
            ]
        },
        {
            "numb": 27,
            "question": "A toaster operating at 240 V has a resistance of 120 Ω. Its power is",
            "answer": "(c) 480 W",
            "options": [
                "(a) 400 W",
                "(b) 2 W",
                "(c) 480 W",
                "(d) 240 W"
            ]
        },
        {
            "numb": 28,
            "question": "A carbon resistor of (47 ± 4.7 ) k Ω to be marked with rings of different colours for its identification. The colour code sequence will be",
            "answer": "b) Yellow – Violet – Orange – Silver",
            "options": [
                "a) Yellow – Green – Violet – Gold",
                "b) Yellow – Violet – Orange – Silver",
                "c) Violet – Yellow – Orange – Silver",
                "d) Green – Orange – Violet – Gold"
            ]
        },
        {
            "numb": 29,
            "question": "Two wires of A and B with circular cross-section are made up of the same material with equal lengths. Suppose RA = 3 RB, then what is the ratio of the radius of wire A to that of B?",
            "answer": "a) 3",
            "options": [
                "a) 3",
                "b) √3",
                "c) 1 /√3",
                "d) 1 /3"
            ]
        },
        {
            "numb": 30,
            "question": "A wire connected to a power supply of 230 V has power dissipation P1. Suppose the wire is cut into two equal pieces and connected parallel to the same power supply. In this case, power dissipation is P2. The ratio P2/p1 is",
            "answer": "(b) 2",
            "options": [
                "(a) 1",
                "(b) 2",
                "(c) 3",
                "(d) 4"
            ]
        },
        {
            "numb": 31,
            "question": "A relation R in a set A is called ____, if (a1, a2) ∈ R implies (a2, a1) ∈ R, for all a1, a2 ∈ A.",
            "answer": "(a) symmetric",
            "options": [
                "(a) symmetric",
                "(b) transitive",
                "(c) equivalence",
                "(d) non-symmetric"
            ]
        },
        {
            "numb": 32,
            "question": "Let R be a relation on the set N of natural numbers defined by nRm if n divides m. Then R is",
            "answer": "(d) Reflexive, transitive but not symmetric",
            "options": [
                "(a) Reflexive and symmetric",
                "(b) Transitive and symmetric",
                "(c) Equivalence",
                "(d) Reflexive, transitive but not symmetric"
            ]
        },
        {
            "numb": 33,
            "question": "The maximum number of equivalence relations on the set A = {1, 2, 3} are",
            "answer": "(d) 5",
            "options": [
                "(a) 1",
                "(b) 2",
                "(c) 3",
                "(d) 5"
            ]
        },
        {
            "numb": 34,
            "question": "If set A contains 5 elements and the set B contains 6 elements, then the number of one-one and onto mappings from A to B is",
            "answer": "(c) 0",
            "options": [
                "(a) 720",
                "(b) 120",
                "(c) 0",
                "(d) none of these"
            ]
        },
        {
            "numb": 35,
            "question": "Let f : [2, ∞) → R be the function defined by f(x) = x^2 – 4x + 5, then the range of f is",
            "answer": "(b) [1, ∞)",
            "options": [
                "(a) R",
                "(b) [1, ∞)",
                "(c) [4, ∞)",
                "(d) [5, ∞)"
            ]
        },
        {
            "numb": 36,
            "question": "Let f : R → R be defined by f(x) = 1/x ∀ x ∈ R. Then f is",
            "answer": "(d) f is not defined",
            "options": [
                "(a) one-one",
                "(b) onto",
                "(c) bijective",
                "(d) f is not defined"
            ]
        },
        {
            "numb": 37,
            "question": "Let A = {1, 2, 3} and consider the relation R = {(1, 1), (2, 2), (3, 3), (1, 2), (2, 3), (1,3)}. Then R is",
            "answer": "(a) reflexive but not symmetric",
            "options": [
                "(a) reflexive but not symmetric",
                "(b) reflexive but not transitive",
                "(c) symmetric and transitive",
                "(d) neither symmetric, nor transitive"
            ]
        },
        {
            "numb": 38,
            "question": "If f : R → R be defined by f(x) = 3x^2 – 5 and g : R → R by g(x) = x/(x^2 + 1), then g o f is",
            "answer": "(a) (3x^2 – 5)/(9x^4 – 30x^2 + 26)",
            "options": [
                "(a) (3x^2 – 5)/(9x^4 – 30x^2 + 26)",
                "(b) (3x^2 – 5)/(9x^4 – 6x^2 + 26)",
                "(c) 3x^2/(x^4 + 2x^2 – 4)",
                "(d) 3x^2/(9x^4 + 30x^2 – 2)"
            ]
        },
        {
            "numb": 39,
            "question": "Let f : R → R be given by f (x) = tan x. Then f^−1(1) is",
            "answer": "(a) π/4",
            "options": [
                "(a) π/4",
                "(b) {n π + π/4 : n ∈ Z}",
                "(c) does not exist",
                "(d) none of these"
            ]
        },
        {
            "numb": 40,
            "question": "If f: R → R be given by f(x) = (3 – x^3)^(1/3), then fof(x) is",
            "answer": "(c) x",
            "options": [
                "(a) x^(1/3)",
                "(b) x^3",
                "(c) x",
                "(d) (3 – x^3)"
            ]
        },
        {
            "numb": 41,
            "question": "Let f : A → B and g : B → C be the bijective functions. Then (g ∘ f)^−1 is",
            "answer": "(a) f^−1 ∘ g^−1",
            "options": [
                "(a) f^−1 ∘ g^−1",
                "(b) f ∘ g",
                "(c) g^−1 ∘ f^−1",
                "(d) g ∘ f"
            ]
        },
        {
            "numb": 42,
            "question": "Consider a binary operation ∗ on N defined as a ∗ b = a^3 + b^3. Choose the correct answer.",
            "answer": "(b) ∗ is commutative but not associative",
            "options": [
                "(a) ∗ is both associative and commutative",
                "(b) ∗ is commutative but not associative",
                "(c) ∗ is associative but not commutative",
                "(d) ∗ is neither commutative nor associative"
            ]
        },
        {
            "numb": 43,
            "question": "Let f : R → R be defined by f(x) = x^2 + 1. Then, pre-images of 17 and –3, respectively, are",
            "answer": "(c) {4, –4}, φ",
            "options": [
                "(a) φ, {4, –4}",
                "(b) {3, –3}, φ",
                "(c) {4, –4}, φ",
                "(d) {4, –4}, {2, –2}"
            ]
        },
        {
            "numb": 44,
            "question": "Set A has 3 elements, and set B has 4 elements. Then the number of injective mappings that can be defined from A to B is",
            "answer": "(c) 24",
            "options": [
                "(a) 144",
                "(b) 12",
                "(c) 24",
                "(d) 64"
            ]
        },
        {
            "numb": 45,
            "question": "Let f : R → R be defined by f(x) = 3x – 4. Then f^−1(x) is given by",
            "answer": "(a) (x + 4)/3",
            "options": [
                "(a) (x + 4)/3",
                "(b) (x/3) – 4",
                "(c) 3x + 4",
                "(d) None of these"
            ]
        },
        {
            "numb": 46,
            "question": "The identity element for the binary operation * defined on Q ~ {0} as a * b = ab/2 ∀ a, b ∈ Q ~ {0} is",
            "answer": "(c) 2",
            "options": [
                "(a) 1",
                "(b) 0",
                "(c) 2",
                "(d) none of these"
            ]
        },
        {
            "numb": 47,
            "question": "Number of binary operations on the set {a, b} are",
            "answer": "(b) 16",
            "options": [
                "(a) 10",
                "(b) 16",
                "(c) 20",
                "(d) 8"
            ]
        },
        {
            "numb": 48,
            "question": "Let A = {1, 2, 3}. Then the number of relations containing (1, 2) and (1, 3), which are reflexive and symmetric but not transitive is",
            "answer": "(a) 1",
            "options": [
                "(a) 1",
                "(b) 2",
                "(c) 3",
                "(d) 4"
            ]
        },
        {
            "numb": 49,
            "question": "Let f , g : R → R be defined by f(x) = 3x + 1 and g(x) = x^2 – 2, ∀ x ∈ R, respectively. Then, f og is",
            "answer": "(b) 3x^2 – 5",
            "options": [
                "(a) 9x^2 + 6x – 1",
                "(b) 3x^2 – 5",
                "(c) 9x^2 – 6x – 3",
                "(d) 3x^2"
            ]
        },
        {
            "numb": 50,
            "question": "The principal value of tan^−1(tan(3π/5)) is",
            "answer": "(b) -2π/5",
            "options": [
                "(a) 2π/5",
                "(b) -2π/5",
                "(c) 3π/5",
                "(d) -3π/5"
            ]
        }
          
                ]*/